[Mystic Nine]
[Adapted from the novel of Kennedy Xu]
[Episode 29]
[This story is purely fictional]
[Li's Residence]
Fifth Master!
Master just told me to invite you over.
Follow me, please.
Master, Fifth Master is here.
You're here, Laogou.
Fifth Master, go ahead.
The Ministry of War has already
planted informants in the Mystic Nine.
Laogou.
You're here.
What a coincidence.
I just told my man to invite you,
and here you are.
Come. Take a seat.
Come.
Take a seat.
I brought a pot of liquor.
Let's calm our nerves.
Sure.
Pour it.
I suppose the Ministry of War spares us now
because they are still looking for an excuse.
They don't want a riot in Changsha
or to antagonize the Mystic Nine.
We are free now.
That's probably because someone
has set a plan in motion.
Who do you think did that?
Xie Jiu or Master Zhang?
Who knows?
Third Master.
What is your next move?
Lay low.
But heed my advice.
At this juncture,
trust
no one.
Come.
A toast to you.
You'll drink first.
What is the meaning of this?
I fear you have poisoned the liquor.
What are you on about?
Are you already drunk before you drink?
Laogou is our friend.
When I had a labor complication back then,
Laogou
and Xie Jiu were there to help me.
That's how I survived.
I won't forget
this kindness from you.
You two have known each other for many years.
You can
overcome this obstacle
and live well.
Trust me.
Stay alive, and you'll find a way out.
Yes.
Staying alive is the most important part.
I'm sorry.
Laogou.
Cheers.
Only these two dishes?
Make two more dishes.
Sure.
Two more dishes.
Enjoy
the liquor.
Laogou.
I need a favor from you.
Consider it my debt to you.
Sure, Third Master.
Tonight,
at dusk,
bring my wife and my son with you
and leave.
What are you planning to do?
I'm crippled. I can't run far.
There are enemies within and outside the city.
They want our lives
and the Mystic Nine.
But the woman and the kid
are innocent.
Throughout my life,
I've only trusted my blade, my account ledger,
and you.
Because you
gave my son
his life.
Third Master.
The Ministry of War
spied on me as I came here.
I might die anytime soon.
If I have to take care of your son as well,
isn't that...
But I know
you're not one who runs away from responsibilities.
Besides,
you're my son's godfather.
I'm begging you now.
Who would have thought
that the Third Master
of the Mystic Nine would beg someone one day?
Changsha
isn't what it used to be.
The Mystic Nine
is also not what it used to be.
However,
as long as I live,
you can rest assured
about your wife and your son's safety.
The food is ready!
Li!
Wu Laogou!
You scoundrel!
I'll kill you.
I'll kill you!
Fifth Master.
What is going on?
Why are you covered in blood?
Fifth Master.
What happened?
It's not mine.
It's Chen Pi's,
Heibei's,
and Li's blood.
I
demolished the Mystic Nine.
What?
Xiangu.
It'll be fine.
♪See the moon, indelible as ink♪
♪As red plum blossoms fall along the street♪
♪Who turns back with a troubled frown?♪
♪See the sky lanterns rise and fall♪
♪If I could take one bright thread from memory♪
♪I'd keep its lingering sweetness in my heart♪
Must I
be this cruel?
You need to convince the Ministry of War
that you are driven by self-interest,
and that you take over the Mystic Nine violently.
♪I drink a cup of rough wine♪
♪Right and wrong pass with the changing seasons♪
♪My heart unchanged, I have no regrets♪
♪However the past may have twisted and turned, I regret nothing with you♪
♪When a thousand sails ride wind and waves home, I'll sail with you again♪
♪When flowers fall and you return, I wish time could turn back♪
♪I'll share with you the lingering taste of new wine♪
♪And get drunk with you♪
♪I♪
♪Will turn the Heavenly Palace upside down♪
[Shared Legacy of Mystic Nine]
♪100,000 Heavenly Soldiers♪
I am Wu Laogou.
A dog breeder.
From now on,
[Fifth]
I am the Fifth Master.
♪I am the Monkey King!♪
♪I laugh boisterously♪
♪Open up!♪
- Breaking news! - Breaking news!
- Eryue Hong was badly burnt!
- One newspaper, please.
- Banjie Li was mortally wounded.
- One newspaper.
- Blood has been spilled!
- Wu Laogou turned on his own!
- Let me read it.
[Mystic Nine in War]
Young boy, give me one.
[Eryue Hong]
[Laogou]
[Mortally wounded]
[Crippled]
Why did you do that?
Why?
Master.
Sir.
Huo Wenhai
must have noticed
that we had met the other day.
So he took the risk
[Changsha Defense Headquarters]
and stole the military seal.
He tried to instigate a rebellion.
Fortunately, your perceptive adjutant
picked up the signs
and went in alone
to kill Huo Wenhai.
Unfortunately,
he lost his life to the cause.
That said,
I've written to the higher-ups
and requested that they
give him the title of Army Captain.
He did not care about the title.
I know.
He was not doing this for the title,
but you.
Huo Wenhai
is dead.
That saved us a lot of trouble.
I have already signed the document
appointing you as the special commissioner
to eliminate the Mystic Nine.
It's on your desk.
I've given you the direction.
Qishan, I hope you know
what
to do.
Nevertheless, I don't think the "kill six to save three" plan
will work.
Wu Laogou
took over the Mystic Nine
when it was at its most vulnerable.
He was ruthless
and killed many people.
In the entirety of Changsha,
he is
the biggest underground force.
Read it.
Today's newspaper.
[Breaking News: The Mystic Nine Might be No More]
[Wu Laogou killed everyone in the Mystic Nine]
A thug is a thug.
You can't change his bloodthirsty nature.
We can't spare someone
like Wu Laogou.
I remember
you two have a feud.
Killing him
should be easy for you, right?
Qishan.
Your world is more than just Changsha.
This place is huge,
but it's insignificant in the grand scheme of things.
A war is upon us.
If you do this well,
I'll nominate you to the Ministry of War.
And then,
you'll have a stage to shine.
We've been friends for many years.
I hope
we can fight together in the future.
You have three days.
After three days,
I'll leave Changsha
for Hengyang for a conference.
Zhang Qishan.
Seize this opportunity.
Otherwise,
it'll be
too late for you to regret it.
[Appoint Zhang Qishan as Special Commissioner]
Master.
Fifth...
Wu Laogou
did turn on
the Mystic Nine.
The newspaper described his crime in a few words,
but the reality
is much worse.
Second Master's late wife
was burned.
Third Master was stabbed to death.
Fourth Master was rendered blind.
Sixth Master was cut many times.
No one knows his fate.
Even Miss Huo was...
Even Miss Huo
was not spared.
He removed her spine.
She probably can't walk anymore.
A scheme.
It's all part of his scheme.
Be it Xiaoyu
or Laogou,
they all fell for Xie Jiu's scheme.
Why couldn't anyone
believe me?
I already said
I could save them all
with my life.
Master!
Master,
you know
very well that they believed what you said.
They knew
that you would carry the burden alone,
so they
had to stop you.
Where is Laogou?
In his dog farm, probably.
Get the car ready.
Eighth Master inherited this from his ancestors.
He said it was the only copy left.
He cherished it
more than he cherished his life.
Master.
Master Zhang...
Master Zhang is here.
The inevitable
has arrived.
Move aside.
Laogou.
What are you planning to achieve?
Look who's here.
The head of the Mystic Nine
or the Changsha Defense Commander?
Whatever you plan is,
share it with me.
We work together,
and maybe, we can both get out of this alive.
You promised me
that you would leave the Mystic Nine
as long as I find Unit 401.
Have you forgotten?
Since you're not part of the Mystic Nine,
then you are a commander,
and I am a bandit.
There's nothing we can talk about.
See them off.
You waited for me
to come here.
Even if I leave the Mystic Nine,
we both know
that
we still need to sort things out in person.
Okay.
I'll allow that.
I took over the Mystic Nine.
We both
have a score to settle.
Wait for me here.
Yes.
We've been through
so many things all these years.
You think I don't know what you're doing?
You went out of your way
to usurp
the other clans.
You want people to think
that you
have taken over the Mystic Nine.
What is your plan?
I need to know everything.
The truth is,
other than you, everyone in the Mystic Nine
has to die.
Xie Jiu told you that?
There was never
a "kill six to save three" plan.
It was all to convince Luo Ang.
The real plan
has always been to kill eight to save one.
Master Zhang.
You already know that,
don't you?
The Ministry of War
will never spare those three clans.
On the surface,
they can spare the women and the opera performer.
But in reality,
they can
just frame them for a crime
and none of them will be spared.
The pivotal information in this matter
is that Luo Ang genuinely wants to save you.
If you live,
the Mystic Nine can live.
Our followers
who rely on us
to fill their tummies can live.
That's why
I must help the Ministry of War
eliminate the other masters
in the Mystic Nine
and take over the Mystic Nine myself.
Then,
the outcome is set in stone.
This
has always been my fight.
I shouldn't have dragged all of you in.
It's my fight.
Not yours!
By your fight,
you mean to sacrifice yourself?
Fine.
So you're sacrificed.
We can leave Changsha safely.
Do you think we can survive?
Do you think
the Ministry of War will spare us?
You still have time.
If you leave now,
you can still live.
Master Zhang!
Why can't you understand this?
Xie Jiu,
Xiaoyu, and I
are trying to save you.
It's not about your life.
We are trying to save Changsha!
You have a war to fight.
You have to protect Changsha, Master Zhang.
Time has changed.
The Mystic Nine is no longer needed,
Master Zhang.
I
finally come to this realization.
The Monkey King is powerful,
but he's still
just a rabble-rousing monkey.
He wreaks havoc in the Heavenly Palace,
but he can't make a new one.
But you can.
You can set up new rules.
You can protect our land
and our people.
So you must live!
Kill me.
Put an end to the whole Mystic Nine saga.
Our people will live in peace.
Kill me.
No.
If I
hadn't dragged you into the Otherworld Tower,
you would still have been the carefree Fifth Master.
It's all
my fault.
I shouldn't have involved you.
There's no turning back.
Let me make the decision for you.
Soon, the newspaper will say
the head of the Mystic Nine, Wu Laogou,
captured and killed the Defense Commander's
Communication Officer.
Then, he tried to assassinate the Defense Commander
to start a riot.
That crime
is enough to have me killed thrice.
Don't do that.
He can cry.
But why are you crying?
Are you going to miss me?
Bring it on.
Forgive me.
[Wu Laogou turned on his own and assassinated government officials]
[Master Zhang captured the murderer to protect the city]
Qishan.
Well done.
You are the reason why we could quell
the riot of the Mystic Nine.
I declare this case an attempt to incite a riot.
The evidence is clear.
According to the military order,
he has to be publicly executed
to serve as a warning to others.
This will demonstrate our strict disciplines
and reassure the people.
Sign it.
Carry out the execution
tomorrow at the hour of Wu.
[Judgment]
I will supervise it personally
to make sure nothing goes wrong.
[Changsha Defense Commander Zhang Qishan]
[Open Execution for Policy Correction]
[Equality for People, Fair Administration]
Master.
Sorry, my friends.
I dragged you into this.
Master.
What are you talking about?
You gave us our lives.
To die with you,
it's worth it.
With all of you next to me,
my trip to the afterlife will be a lively one.
Perhaps even the ghosts
will be afraid of us.
That's right.
Master.
You are the Monkey King.
In the Underworld,
we'll do something great together.
We'll beat up the little imps,
and fight our way back to the Heavenly Palace.
That's right!
Master!
We will die with you!
Good.
Wu and his cohort of thugs
possessed illegal arms,
murdered government officials,
and disrupted the societal peace.
[Judgment]
They are found guilty of their crimes.
In accordance with Section 16 of the Criminal Code of Armed Forces
and Section 2 of the Bandits Regulations Ordinance,
they will be sentenced to death
immediately.
Can I talk to him?
Laogou.
Any last words?
I knew this day would come.
I thought I could change my fate
if you left the Mystic Nine.
In the end,
I still
couldn't escape
your control.
Your shackles
did not come from me,
but you.
♪Recognizing you through the smoke of war♪
Can I ask for one last favor from you?
That nobody
has no right to take my life.
We know each other so well.
Master Zhang.
♪You sit in your lone city while I protect my hometown♪
Send me off.
♪I dip my brush into the western wind to paint the setting sun♪
♪The returning ravens are too noisy, how can I fight back?♪
♪The land turns barren and old, the memories come flooding back♪
♪Every moment with you appears in my heart♪
♪My burning heart turns ashen, my hair turns white♪
♪I look at you whilst I yearn for you♪
♪The land is barren, the snow is thick, the longing is endless♪
♪Thousand miles apart, with whom are you enjoying the good moments?♪
♪It's just a dream, it's just my duty♪
♪Trading my life for your safety♪
♪Holding a pool of autumn water, we share the same robe♪
Sir.
Wu and his cohorts have been executed.
From now on,
hunt down the Mystic Nine.
It shall not rise again.
♪The land is barren, the snow is thick, the longing is endless♪
♪Thousand miles apart, with whom are you enjoying the good moments?♪
♪It's just a dream, it's just my duty♪
♪Trading my life for your safety♪
[20 Years Later]
My fellow audience,
listen well.
I shall tell you
a story now.
The tales of the martial arts world
are like the moon.
It's not full when you want it to be.
It's crescent when you don't want it to be.
As the saying goes,
the raging tide of time
will wash away different eras of heroes.
Just like this,
the prestigious Mystic Nine
that once settled in here
is now left
without even a plaque.
Some say that they were bandits.
Some say
they were protectors of the people.
Are they good or evil,
a boon or a bane?
No one knows.
It really shows us
that as grand as the martial arts world can be,
no one can survive the changing of time.
So what happened to Master Zhang?
Where did he go?
I grew up here,
and I've never
heard of a person called Master Zhang.
And Wu Laogou
died just like that?
And Chen Pi
is blind.
How is he going to fight now?
And Huo Xiangu,
is anyone taking care of her?
She's a prideful woman.
She won't just lie on the bed all her life.
And what about Qi Tiezui?
Isn't he a seer?
He didn't predict the bad outcome?
All right. All right.
You sure have a lot of questions.
But there are certain things
in this world
that have no answer.
Some of them
become legends.
That's all I know
about the Mystic Nine.
As to what happens later,
I have no idea.
Anyway,
look.
It's getting late.
Go back home and eat.
If you want more stories,
come here again tomorrow.
All right.
They already went back.
Why are you still here?
I don't like this story.
The Mystic Nine
shouldn't end like this.
Sir,
are you telling
a true story,
or did you make it up?
If you made it up,
can you...
Can you change the ending?
Let them live.
Master Zhang won't leave.
Wu Laogou won't die.
They drink and eat
together,
and have a good time.
♪The past fades like smoke♪
♪A choice is made in silence♪
♪In this labyrinthine puzzle♪
♪Who can reach the shore?♪
♪Just an ordinary farewell♪
♪The sun seems to shine bright over our heads♪
♪But this could be our last trip together♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Take care♪
♪We once raced♪
♪For the dawn♪
♪Ever-lasting bond, a satisfying vindication♪
♪In the web of fate♪
♪No one can escape♪
♪Life and death cut like a blade♪
♪We too were young once♪
♪Fortunate to brave the raging waves together♪
♪Keep the ember lit♪
♪To illuminate the journey ahead♪
♪The spring breeze continues outside♪
♪Who was it who left in such haste?♪
♪Caught in the game, the raging waves fall silent♪
♪Who believes in fate?♪
♪For my home and my country, the years pass like a dream♪
♪When the song ends, who will still be waiting?♪
♪With a nod, we bid farewell and set out again♪
♪Please, do take care of yourself♪